<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Racheltomi</title><link>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Racheltomi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2019, Weru and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How You Can Design Delightful API Architecture</title><link>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/architecture/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/architecture/</guid><description>Building, designing, and consuming APIs are some of the most important aspects of every developer&amp;rsquo;s career. An API should reflect the needs of users and, in this case, developers like you. As an app developer, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to do one of two things:
● communicate with external sources (i.e., third-party APIs) that provide the information you need
● build an internal API for your company app or personal project
However, it&amp;rsquo;s important to make your API easily accessible and flexible.</description></item><item><title>Differences Between Browser Router and Hash Router</title><link>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/routers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/routers/</guid><description>Introduction to Routing in React Routing is a very important aspect of every website. In react Js, routing is a process that allows a user to navigate to the different URLs that make up a react application. This is made possible through the use of a standard library system called React Router. With react-router, we can define multiple routes in our applications and render different components present in the app based on the route that matches the current URL being used.</description></item><item><title>Validating Props in React Components Using PropTypes</title><link>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/proptypes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/proptypes/</guid><description>Proptypes is a package that is used to check how data types flows between react components. It’s a runtime type checking that helps to validate props passed between react components.
Why do we Need PropTypes? When writing react, it is easy to mistakenly pass the wrong props to a component, which causes a bug that can be difficult to track down especially when building big projects with lots of components. JavaScript functions accept data of different types without throwing an error even if it’s not what’s expected.</description></item><item><title>5 CSS Selectors You Should Start Using as a Developer</title><link>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/css-selectors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/css-selectors/</guid><description>Introduction When I started writing CSS, I only learned how to use class, Id, types and space selectors and I thought that was all to it. With time, I learnt more about new selectors and I’ll be sharing some of them with you in this article. CSS selectors are used to target or select HTML elements that you want to style. There are wide variety of CSS selectors available, but for the purpose of this article, I’ll be discussing just 5 of these selectors;</description></item><item><title>How to Use Local Storage in JavaScript</title><link>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/localstorage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/localstorage/</guid><description>I will say I’ve never heard about local storage since I started to learn JavaScript, not until I had to build a simple project for personal development and I needed to store my data somewhere. The best option available was local storage and yeah, that was my first time hearing the word “local storage”.
I made a documentation of what I learnt and I’ve decided to share them with you in this article.</description></item><item><title>How to spend more time not coding as a Freelance Developer</title><link>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/notcoding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.racheltomi.work/post/notcoding/</guid><description>You were expecting some new tech, right? Not today!
You’re always on a tight deadline, learning a new framework or looking to deploy a new project ASAP. The list is endless and they all seem important. You wish you could spend more time with loved ones and have fun. I understand! As developers, we usually don&amp;rsquo;t pay attention to work-life balance, and the kudos given to spending more time in front of the screen is becoming unhealthy.</description></item></channel></rss>